Ian Blanshard Biomedical Scientist

07709958850 / Ian246@hotmail.co.uk

Summary

I am a HCPC registered Biomedical Scientist working in microbiology, with 8 years' experience working in clinical laboratories, using a range of automated and manual techniques. In my role I perform highly technical and interpretive work whilst conforming to standard operating procedures (SOPs), health and safety procedures, organizational policies and good laboratory practice.

Every laboratory I have worked in has had a comprehensive quality management system and are accredited to ISO 15189, I have taken part in meetings, offered improvements which have been implemented and performed auditing of current procedures to seek continual improvement of the service, I am personally committed to continual professional development (CPD) to ensure high quality of my own work.

I have taken part in multidisciplinary team meetings, in many of my roles have trained other staff and have previous managerial experience which has helped develop my excellent communications skills.

Employment History

Biomedical Scientist

January 2021 - Present

Public Health Wales Microbiology Glan Clwyd Hospital, LL18 5UJ

- Identification of pathogens utilizing various methods
- Working to SOPs as part of a comprehensive Quality management system
- Using and controlling substances hazardous to health (COSHH)
- ISO 15189 Accredited laboratory

Healthcare Science Apprentice September 2016 – December 2021

Mid-Cheshire NHS Trust - Microbiology Dept Macclesfield District General Hospital, SK10 3BL

- Completed IBMS registration portfolio
- Achieved HCPC registration
- Awarded 1st class BSc
- Performing the role of trainee BMS

Medical Laboratory Assistant

May 2015 - August 2016

Mid-Cheshire NHS Trust - Microbiology Dept Macclesfield District General Hospital, SK10 3BL

- Receiving and processing patient samples
- Training other members of staff
- Managing stock/reagents required for laboratory
- Disposal of hazardous waste in line with The Hazardous Waste (England and Wales)Regulations 2005

Duty Manager

November 2011 - May 2015

Co-operative Food East-Cheshire (various stores)

- Managing staff
- Cashing up and performing banking
- Delivering on KPI's
- Key holding duties

Education

BSc Healthcare Science – Infection Science (1st)

Staffordshire University Stoke-On-Trent ST4 2DE

BTEC Level 3 - Graphic Design (Distinction)

Macclesfield College Park Lane SK11 8LF

GCSE - (10x A-C, including A Maths, AA Science double award)

Poynton High School Yew Tree Lane SK12 1PU

References

Available upon request